paylease.com 2019-03-17

# Privacy Policy | PayLease

Last updated: March 17, 2017

Privacy is important to PayLease LLC and we want you to be familiar with how we collect, use and disclose information. This Privacy Policy describes our practices in connection with information that we collect through websites operated by us from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (the “ **Websites** ”), through the software applications made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices (the “ **Apps** ”), through our social media pages that we control from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (collectively, our “ **Social Media Pages** ”) as well as through HTML-formatted email messages that we send to you that link to this Privacy Policy, (collectively, including the Websites, the Apps and our Social Media Pages, the “ **Services** ”). By providing Personal Information to us, you agree to this Privacy Policy.

## Personal Information

**Personal Information We May Collect**

“ **Personal Information** ” is information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable person, including:

  * Name
  * Postal address (including billing and residential addresses)
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Credit and debit card number
  * Account number
  * Social media account ID
  * Resident ID, if applicable

We may use a third-party payment service to process payments made through the Services. When you make a payment through the Services, your Personal Information may be collected by such third party and not by us, and will be subject to the third party’s privacy policy, rather than this Privacy Policy. We have no control over, and are not responsible for, this third party’s collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information.

If you submit any Personal Information relating to other people to us or to our service providers in connection with the Services, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**How We May Collect Personal Information**

We and our service providers may collect Personal Information in a variety of ways, including:

  * **Through the Services** : We may collect Personal Information through the Services, e.g., when you create an account or make a rental payment to your landlord through our Services, make a payment to your homeowners association, or engage in any other type of transaction with us.
  * **Offline** : We may collect Personal Information from you offline, such as when you fill out a lease application at one of the properties that uses our services or if you contact customer service.
  * **From Other Sources** : We may receive your Personal Information from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, social media platforms (including from people with whom you are friends or otherwise connected), landlords, property managers and others on whose behalf we may process transactions, and from other third parties including fraud prevention services. In addition, if you elect to connect your social media account to your Website account, certain Personal Information from your social media account will be shared with us, which may include Personal Information that is part of your profile or your friends’ profiles.

**How We May Use Personal Information**

We and our service providers may use Personal Information:

  * To process rental payments, homeowner dues, or other payment obligations you make to your landlord, homeowners association, and or other entities on whose behalf we process payments, and to provide you with related customer service or otherwise communicate with you regarding such transactions (including providing payment confirmations).
  * To send administrative information to you, for example, information regarding the Services and changes to our terms, conditions and policies.
  * To send you marketing communications that we believe may be of interest to you, consistent with your choices.
  * To personalize your experience on the Services by presenting products and offers tailored to you.
  * To facilitate social sharing functionality.
  * For our business purposes, such as data analysis, customer onboarding, audits, fraud monitoring and prevention, developing new products, enhancing, improving or modifying our Services, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and operating and expanding our business activities.

**How Personal Information May Be Disclosed**

Your Personal Information may be disclosed:

  * To our affiliates for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
  * To our service providers who provide services such as website hosting, data analysis, payment processing, fraud prevention and risk management, order fulfillment, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, email delivery, auditing and other services.
  * To our partners, including property managers, landlords, homeowners’ associations and others on whose behalf we process transactions including rental payments, association fees and dues, and other transactions.
  * By you, on message boards, chat, profile pages and blogs and other services to which you are able to post information and materials (including, without limitation, our Social Media Pages), if applicable. Please note that any information you post or disclose through these services will become public and may be available to other users and the general public. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose any information on the Services.
  * To a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

**Other Collection, Uses and Disclosures**

We also may collect, use and disclose your Personal Information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, which may include laws outside your country of residence; (b) to respond to requests from courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies, and other public and government authorities, which may include such authorities outside your country of residence; (c) to enforce our terms and conditions; and (d) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others.

## Other Information

**Other Information We May Collect**

“ **Other Information** ” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an identifiable individual, such as:

  * Browser and device information
  * App usage data
  * Information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies
  * Demographic information and other information provided by you
  * Aggregated information

If we are required to treat Other Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then we may use it for the purposes for which we use and disclose Personal Information as detailed in this Policy.

**How We May Collect Other Information**

We and our service providers may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including:

  * **Through your browser or device** : Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, Internet browser type and version and the name and version of the Services (such as the App) you are using. We use this information to ensure that the Services function properly.
  * **Through your use of the App** : When you download and use the App, we and our service providers may track and collect App usage data, such as the date and time the App on your device accesses our servers and what information and files have been downloaded to the App based on your device number.
  * **Using cookies** : Cookies are pieces of information stored directly on the computer that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on the Services, pages visited, language preferences, and other anonymous traffic data. We and our service providers use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, to personalize your experience while using the Services and to recognize your computer in order to assist your use of the Services. We also gather statistical information about use of the Services in order to continually improve their design and functionality, understand how they are used and assist us with resolving questions regarding them. Cookies further allow us to select which of our advertisements or offers are most likely to appeal to you and display them while you are on the Services. We may also use cookies or other technologies to track responses to our online advertisements.

If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies or be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer to your computer of a particular cookie (or cookies) from a particular site. You may also wish to refer to <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html>. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the Services. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer, and you may need to log in every time you visit. You also may not receive advertising or other offers from us that are relevant to our services and your interests and needs.

  * **Using pixel tags and** **other similar technologies** : Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used in connection with some Services to, among other things, track the actions of users of the Services (including email recipients), measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about usage of the Services and response rates.

We do not respond to browser do-not-track signals at this time.

  * **Analytics**. We use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use of the Services and report on activities and trends.  This service may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources.  You can learn about Google’s practices by going to [google.com/policies/privacy/‌partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.
  * **IP Address** : Your IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses the Services, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. Collecting IP addresses is standard practice and is done automatically by many websites, applications and other services. We use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating usage levels, diagnosing server problems and administering the Services. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP address.
  * **From you** : Information such as your preferred means of communication is collected when you voluntarily provide it.
  * **By aggregating information** : Aggregated Personal Information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Services (for example, we may aggregate Personal Information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code).

**How We May Use and Disclose Other Information**

We may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. In some instances, we may combine Other Information with Personal Information (such as combining your name with your location). If we do, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information as long as it is combined.

## Third Party Services

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site or service to which the Services link, including but not limited to any other site or service associated with your landlord, homeowners’ association, property management company, or others. The inclusion of a link on the Services does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us or by our affiliates.

In addition, we are not responsible for the information collection, use, disclosure or security policies or practices of other organizations, such as Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM or any other app developer, app provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including with respect to any Personal Information you disclose to other organizations through or in connection with the Apps.

## Security

We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Information within our organization. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of your account has been compromised), please immediately notify us in accordance with the _“Contacting Us”_ section below.

## Choices and Access

**Your choices regarding our use of your Personal Information**

If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails from us on a going-forward basis, you may opt-out by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in such emails.

We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you opt-out of receiving marketing-related emails from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, from which you cannot opt-out.

**How you can access, change or suppress your Personal Information**

If you would like to review, correct, update, suppress or delete Personal Information that you have previously provided to us, you may contact us by email at [support@paylease.com](mailto:support@paylease.com) or mail at:

PayLease, LLC  
ATTN: Privacy  
9330 Scranton Road, Suite 450  
San Diego, CA 92121

In your request, please make clear what Personal Information you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your Personal Information suppressed from our database or otherwise let us know what limitations you would like to put on our use of your Personal Information. For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the Personal Information associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping and reporting purposes, including but not limited to compliance with laws relating to anti-money laundering and counter-terrorist financing, and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting a change or deletion (e.g., when you make a lease payment, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Information provided until after the completion of such payment). There may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed.

## Use of Services by Minors

The Services are not directed to individuals under the age of thirteen (13), and we request that they not provide Personal Information through the Services.

## Jurisdiction and Cross-Border Transfer

The Services are controlled and operated by us from the United States and are not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and by using the Services you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, including the United States, which may have data protection rules that are different from those of your country. In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other countries may be entitled to access your personal information

## Sensitive Information

Unless specifically requested, we ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive Personal Information ( _e.g._ , social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, or criminal background) on or through the Services or otherwise to us.

## Updates to this Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy. The “ _Last Updated_ ” legend at the top of this page indicates when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Services. Your use of the Services following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [support@paylease.com](mailto:support@paylease.com) or mail at:

PayLease, LLC  
ATTN: Privacy  
9330 Scranton Road, Suite 450  
San Diego, CA 92121

Because email communications are not always secure, please do not include credit card or other sensitive information in your emails to us.
